=The Origin of Eternity=
= أصل الخلود =
=Episode 17=
= الحلقة 17 =
(Immense Bliss)
(النعيم الهائل)
You're still not willing to see me?
ما زلت غير مستعد لرؤيتي؟
I've been learning
كنت أتعلم
how to play guqin from the guqin expert in the palace.
كيف تلعب guqin من خبير guqin في القصر.
Only then,
حينها فقط،
I found out
اكتشفت
that the song you played for me
أن الأغنية التي عزفتها من أجلي
was called Song of Courtship.
كانت تسمى أغنية الخطوبة.
You're finally willing to see me now.
أنت في النهاية على استعداد لرؤيتي الآن.
Your Majesty, you should stop playing
جلالة الملك ، يجب أن تتوقف عن اللعب
such decadent music.
مثل هذه الموسيقى المنحطة.
So, the crown prince of the Ling Empire
إذن ، ولي عهد إمبراطورية لينغ
is actually well-versed in such decadent music.
هو في الواقع ضليع في مثل هذه الموسيقى المنحطة.
It's no wonder the Ling Empire
لا عجب في إمبراطورية لينغ
couldn't defeat the Great Sheng.
لم يستطع هزيمة Great Sheng.
I thought
اعتقدت
you would feel happier
ستشعر بسعادة أكبر
when you listen to my playing.
عندما تستمع إلى عزفتي.
Your Majesty, you visit the courier hostel every day.
جلالة الملك ، تزور نزل البريد السريع كل يوم.
Aren't you afraid that people might gossip about you?
ألا تخشى أن يثرثر الناس عليك؟
I just wanted to see you.
أردت فقط أن أراك.
Your Majesty, you've seen me now.
جلالة الملك ، لقد رأيتني الآن.
Please return.
عد من فضلك.
(I wonder if he has taken his medicine on time for the past few days?)
(أتساءل عما إذا كان قد تناول دوائه في الوقت المحدد خلال الأيام القليلة الماضية؟)
(I wonder how his recovery is going?)
(أتساءل كيف تسير عملية شفائه؟)
There's an assassin.
هناك قاتل.
Don't be afraid.
لا تخافوا.
I'll protect you.
سأحميك.
However, you need to give me something in return.
ومع ذلك ، عليك أن تعطيني شيئًا في المقابل.
Someone!
شخص ما!
Take him to the imperial cell!
خذه إلى الزنزانة الإمبراطورية!
Yes, Your Majesty!
نعم يا صاحب الجلالة!
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك ،
you're hurt.
أنت مجروح.
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
Bai Ze,
باي زي ،
the incident about the Third Prince
حادثة الأمير الثالث
will be my last time lying to you.
ستكون آخر مرة أكذب عليك.
Can you forgive me?
هل تستطيع مسامحتي؟
I still cannot bring myself to hate you.
ما زلت لا أستطيع أن أكرهك بنفسي.
Return to the palace with me.
العودة إلى القصر معي.
This place is unsafe.
هذا المكان غير آمن.
You are?
أنت؟
Your Majesty, you once said
جلالة الملك ، كما قلت ذات مرة
that you wanted me to stay with you.
أنك تريدني أن أبقى معك.
I have no way to repay you
ليس لدي طريقة لسداد لك
for saving my life.
لإنقاذ حياتي.
I can only offer myself to you.
لا يسعني إلا أن أقدم نفسي لك.
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك ،
are you willing to accept me?
هل انت على استعداد لقبولني
I never expected you
لم أتوقعك أبدا
to say something like that.
لقول شيء من هذا القبيل.
♪Fearless, the falling flowers love the eastern river♪
♪ بلا خوف ، الزهور المتساقطة تحب النهر الشرقي
♪All for nothing, resembling someone we know♪
كل شيء مقابل لا شيء ، يشبه شخصًا نعرفه
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك ،
♪I fear the past perishes in a flash♪
♪ أخشى أن يموت الماضي في ومضة ♪
tonight,
الليلة،
♪And more, I fear travelling the world alone♪
♪ وأكثر من ذلك ، أخشى السفر حول العالم وحدي
I'm yours.
أنا لك.
♪Reminiscing the memories amidst tipsiness♪
♪ استحضار الذكريات وسط النشوة ♪
♪Missing out on the loved one while growing old♪
♪ فقدان من تحب أثناء تقدمك في العمر ♪
♪I fear the past perishes in a flash♪
♪ أخشى أن يموت الماضي في ومضة ♪
♪I even fear thinking of the sky meeting the sea♪
♪ حتى أنني أخشى التفكير في لقاء السماء بالبحر
♪Every visit to the mortal realm, meeting you brings more suffering♪
♪ في كل زيارة إلى عالم البشر ، يجلب لك مقابلتك المزيد من المعاناة
♪There's no love in the world that brings no tears♪
♪ لا يوجد حب في العالم لا يبكي
Later, I'll tell the Secretariat to draft up an imperial edict.
لاحقًا ، سأطلب من الأمانة العامة صياغة مرسوم إمبراطوري.
I will appoint you as The Monarch of Great Sheng.
سأعينك ملك شينغ العظيم.
That's unnecessary.
هذا غير ضروري.
What are you saying?
ماذا تقول؟
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك ،
I said this last night.
لقد قلت هذا الليلة الماضية.
I offered myself to you
قدمت نفسي لك
to repay you for saving me.
لسداد لك لإنقاذي.
Your Majesty, I'm grateful
جلالة الملك ، أنا ممتن
that you're willing
الذي ترغب فيه
to appoint me as the monarch.
لتعيينني كملك.
However,
لكن،
I'm already tired of the mind games they play here.
لقد سئمت بالفعل من الألعاب الذهنية التي يلعبونها هنا.
Your Majesty, it's better for you to seek another partner.
جلالة الملك ، من الأفضل لك أن تبحث عن شريك آخر.
♪Wandered off from the crowd♪
تجول بعيدًا عن الحشد ♪
♪As more wonderful things await♪
♪ كما تنتظر المزيد من الأشياء الرائعة
♪A sunset from the past resurfaced♪
انعكاس غروب الشمس من الماضي
♪Thousands of sailboats drifted in the sea of clouds♪
جرفت آلاف المراكب الشراعية في بحر السحب
♪And docked at different piers♪
♪ ورست على أرصفة مختلفة ♪
♪Only the catkin willow and my graying hair remained♪
فقط صفصاف القطة وشعري الشيب بقي
♪Let's take on♪
♪ لنأخذ
♪Another year♪
♪ سنة أخرى ♪
♪I traveled alone toward daytime as I waved aside the night♪
سافرت لوحدي في النهار بينما كنت ألوح جانباً في الليل
♪The tapping rain♪
مطر التنصت ♪
♪Awakened the sorrow♪
أيقظ الحزن
♪I'm crying out in loneliness amid pandemonium♪
♪ أنا أبكي في عزلة وسط الهرج والمرج
♪I endured countless ordeals from worldly entanglement♪
لقد تحملت محن لا حصر لها من التشابك الدنيوي ♪
♪Knowing how difficult things are for the first time♪
معرفة مدى صعوبة الأمور لأول مرة ♪
♪After you overcome the vicissitudes of life♪
بعد أن تتغلب على تقلبات الحياة
♪Only then do you understand the fickleness of the world♪
"عندها فقط تفهم تقلب العالم"
♪I wanted to enjoy the years but it turned into a disaster overnight♪
♪ أردت الاستمتاع بالسنوات لكنها تحولت إلى كارثة بين عشية وضحاها
♪Knowing that I can't turn back time♪
♪ مع العلم أنني لا أستطيع العودة بالزمن ♪
♪You would not be intoxicated by sorrow♪
لن تسكر بالحزن
♪Until you were embroiled in love♪
حتى تتورط في الحب ♪
♪I wanted to enjoy the years but it turned into a disaster overnight♪
♪ أردت الاستمتاع بالسنوات لكنها تحولت إلى كارثة بين عشية وضحاها
♪Knowing that I can't turn back time♪
♪ مع العلم أنني لا أستطيع العودة بالزمن ♪
♪You would not be intoxicated by sorrow♪
لن تسكر بالحزن
♪Until you were embroiled in love♪
حتى تتورط في الحب ♪